COLIN STELL - Full Stack Web-Developer

e-mail: colinjohnstell@gmail.com | phone: (303)249-5548 |

<u>linkedin.com/colinstell | github.com/ColinStellDev96 | colinstell.com</u>

SUMMARY:

Full Stack Web-Developer with experience as a Project Manager in a digital design agency. Creativity driven and passionate about using technology to bring design to life. Through my experience as a project manager and my education in full stack web-development working with JavaScript technologies, my goal is to continue to develop these skills to be an asset on the teams I work with.

FUNCTIONAL EXPERTISE

- Front-End Development
- Back-End Development
- Project Management

- JavaScript Technologies
- Time Management
- Client Service

RELEVANT PROJECTS:

- The Cigar Lounge App: This was the final project for CodeCraft School of Technology. Users are able to sign-up/login and use the application to keep track of the cigars they have enjoyed. This single-page application was created using JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, Vue.js, and Mongoose along with Bootstrap to help with styling. I created my own database of 140 cigars for the Minimum Viable Product using a JSON data format. cigarloungeapp.com (2017)
- NASA Asteroid API App: Used NASA's public API and JSON/AJAX to display data about "near earth asteroids." Users are able to select any date from a date selector and the Asteroid data for name, velocity, distance from earth, and diameter appears in a styled table. colinstell.com/asteroid/ (2017)
- **Richtr Financial Studio:** As Project Manager I was tasked with managing our design, development and strategy teams for this rebranding project along with also leading team and client meetings. I was also the primary copywriter for the project and was integral in the naming of the new brand. <u>richtr.io</u> (2016)

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE:

CodeCraft School of Technology

July 2017 – September 2017

Full Time Full-Stack Web Development Student

12 week, immersive, bootcamp offering a professional certificate in full-stack web development.

- During this immersive training program, I worked on a wide variety of projects that required the use of the following technologies: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, Vue.js, MongoDB/Mongoose, Git/GitHub, AJAX, and JSON.
- Worked, on average, for 60+ hours a week in class and working on assignments after class.
- Focused heavily on logic-heavy back-end engineering, front-end design, and user experience.

Human Design

May 2016 – April 2017

Creative Producer

A design agency in Boulder, CO with 10-25 employees and with clients/partners like Vulcan, Discovery, Bike Magazine, Rayback Collective, Richtr Financial Studio.

- Managed software development projects, UX design projects, and branding engagements from start to finish.
- Worked in fast paced, highly autonomous environments where I was trusted to keep projects on time and on budget based on the contracts signed and change orders.

- Facilitated meetings with client executive teams (CEOs, CTOs, and Directors) along with our internal teams.
- Worked on successful projects with more than 10 different companies, ranging in duration from 2 weeks 6 months, and with budgets ranging from \$30K \$500K.

The Table Church Music Director July 2016 – June 2017

A local church in Lafayette, CO with an average of 130 people per week for Sunday service.

- Led and scheduled music and production teams on a weekly basis for Sunday morning church services.
- Teams included: Music, sound/tech, setup/tear-down teams.
- Tasked with training team leaders and communicating with them to help lead each of these teams.
- Worked with church website via Squarespace weekly to upload sermon audio to the site.

Fresh Thymes Eatery

September 2013 – April 2016

Line Chef

A local gluten-free and organic start-up eatery in Boulder, CO that became a \$1M company in its first year as a business.

- Started two weeks after the restaurant opened and quickly jumped into a role of helping establish the kitchen culture as we worked through the ups and downs of starting a new restaurant.
- Responsible for opening the restaurant 5 days a week, this included all preparation and leading the lunch hours.
- Trained most of the cooks that started with Fresh Thymes and helped evaluate potential employees.
- Communicated with front-of-the-house managers and kitchen managers daily to make sure operations ran as smoothly as possible.
- Managed all incoming customer orders in a fast-paced environment everyday, making sure food went out within 10 15 minutes and worked through any issues that arose.

EDUCATION:

CodeCraft School of Technology (Full Stack Web-Development) - Boulder, CO.

July - September 2017

• 12 Week, Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp with focus on MEVN Stack Javascript Technologies.

Front Range Community College - Westminster, CO.

August 2011 - May 2012

• History, Music Theory, and English Classes

Black Hills State University - Spearfish, SD

August 2006 - May 2007

• Speech, English, Music, Wellness, and History Classes

SKILLS:

Full-Stack Web Development, Project Management, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB/Mongoose, Vue.js, JSON, AJAX, Git/Github, Command Line, Squarespace, Atom, Copywriting, Responsive Design, RESTful API's.